have you ever been in an argument about
nuclear power
we have and we found it frustrating and
confusing
so let's try and get to grips with this
topic wall
done
of it all started in the nineteen
forties
after the shock and horror the wall in
the use of the atomic bomb
nuclear energy promise to be a peaceful
spinoff love the new technology
helping the world get back on its feet
everyone's
imagination was running wild would an
atrocity become frame
could nuclear power help settle the
antarctic would there be nuclear powered
cars
planes all houses it seems that this was
just a few years of hard work away
one thing was certain: the future was
atomic just a few years later there was
a sort of Atomic Age Hanover
as it turned out nuclear power was a
very complicated
and very expensive turning physics into
engineering was easy on paper but hard
in real life
also private companies thought the
nuclear power was much too risky
as an investment most of them would much
rather stick with gas
coal and oil but there were many people
who didn't just want to abandon the
promise of the Atomic Age
an exciting new technology the prospect
to enormously cheap
electricity the prospective being
independent oil and gas imports
and in some cases a secret desire to
possess
atomic weapons provided a strong
motivation to keep going
nuclear power supply finest hour finally
came in the early nineteen seventies
when war in the Middle East caused oil
prices to skyrocket worldwide
now commercial interest and investment
picked up on it.
dazzling pace more than harmful all the
nuclear reactors in the world
were built between 1970 in 1985 but
which typeof reacted to build
given how many different types there
were to choose from a surprising
underdog candidate won the day
the light water reactor it wasn't very
innovative
and it wasn't too popular with
scientists but it had some decisive
advantages
it was there it works and it wasn't
terribly expensive
so what does a light-water reactor do
well
the basic principle is shockingly simple
it heats up water
using an artificial chain reaction
nuclear fission releases several million
times more energy than any chemical
reaction could
rainy heavy elements on the brink of
stability like uranium 235
get bombarded with neutrons the neutron
is absorbed
but the resulting is unstable most to
the time
it immediately spits into fast-moving
blaze ornaments some
additional free neutrons and energy in
the form of radiation
the radiation heats the surrounding
water while the neutrons repeat the
process with
other items releasing more neutrons and
radiation in a closely controlled chain
reaction
very different from the fast destructive
runaway reaction
in an atomic bomb in our light-water
reactor
a moderator is needed to control the
neutrons energy simple
ordinary water does the job which is
very practical since water is used right
the turbines anyway
the light water reactor became prevalent
because it's simple and cheap
however it's neither the safest most
efficient
know technically elegant nuclear reactor
the renewed nuclear Hyde
lasted barely a decade though in 1979
the Three Mile Island nuclear plant in
Pennsylvania barely escaped a
catastrophe
when it's called mounted in 1986 the
Chernobyl catastrophe directly
threatened Central Europe with a
radioactive cloud
banded 2011 the drawn-out Fukushima
disaster sparks new discussions and
concerns
while in the nineteen eighties 218 new
nuclear power reactors went live
their number and nucleus global share of
the electricity production
has stagnated since the end of the
eighties
so what's the situation today today
nuclear energy meets around 10 percent
to the world's energy demand
that are about 439 nuclear reactors
in 31 countries about 70 new reactors
under construction in 2015
most at the main countries which are
growing quickly all in all
160 new reactors are planned worldwide
most nuclear reactors will build more
than 25 years ago
with pretty old technology more than
eighty percent
are various times in life
water reactor today many countries are
faced with the choice
the expensive replacement of the aging
reactors possibly with more efficient
but
last tested models or a move away from
nuclear power
towards Newark or older technology was
different cost
and environmental impacts so should we
use nuclear energy
the pro and contra arguments will be
presented him next week
subscribe and then you won't miss it our
channel has a new sponsor
or to Bordeaux com if you use the URL
audible dot com slash nutshell
you can get a free audiobook and support
our channel
producing how videos takes lot of time
and we feel a lot of this by listening
to audiobooks
for ready entertaining book we recommend
into the net by Jon Krakauer
he's a great writer and the story is
really absorbing and true
go to audible dot com slash nutshell to
get the book for free
thanks a lot to audible for supporting
our channel and to you for watching